# **SANI MUHAMMAD SANI**

## **DATA ANALYST**

+234 8089 8784 68 +234 8063 0554 17 || muhammadsanijae@gmail.com || https://github.com/sanijae https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-sani-9564a722a || Zaria Kaduna State, Nigeria

## **Summary:**

Dedicated Data Analyst with in-depth knowledge of research methodologies and data visualization. Proven experience modeling structured and unstructured data and working with large data sets. Passionate about learning new concepts and an excellent team player.

## **Work Experience:**

## Data Analyst – Quantum Analytics NG January 2023

- Performed data cleaning, transformation, Dashboard and report presentation and Collaborate with other teams and work together.
- Compiled database by creating tables documenting application functions
- Store, organize and examined data by creating data warehouse server.
- Engage end-to-end data collection process using qualitative and quantitative methods for 50+ projects
- Recommended upgrade that improved platform architecture in response to internal audits concerning system performance recovery.
- Collaborating with 100+ data analyst, data scientist and projects managers on several concurrent projects Q1 2023.

## Junior Software Developer Internship – ICICT Abu Zaria 2019 - 2022

- Performed automated testing task and developed complex features routinely.
- Work independently, while serving as an effective and enthusiastic collaborator.
- Analyzed business requirement to derived technical software design and performance requirements.
- Developed code flow security best practice and design pattern
- Implement and update application module under the supervision of senior developers.

#### SQL Developer - NILEST Zaria 2017 - 2020

- Identified opportunities to improved data visualization and analysis
- Maintained tested and upgrade database tables and columns if required
- Extract data from files and used transformation technique to clean data as per requirements.
- Developed and presented findings and solution to audience including senior executives' and stakeholders'
- Input data from employee survey reports
- Provide administrative assistance to information technology team

## **Education:**

M.Sc. Artificial Intelligence Abu Zaria 2021 – Current

B.Sc. Computer Science Umaru Musa Yar'adua University, Katsina 2016 – 2019

#### **Hard Skills**

- PowerBI, Tableau and Excel
- Data Collection
- Data Mining
- Data Modelling
- Database Management
- Data Warehousing
- Data Visualization
- Data Analytics
- Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn and Scikit-learn.
- Machine Learning algorithms
- Python Programming
- R programming
- Java, C++, C# and JavaScript
- MySQL, PosqresSQL, MSSQL and MongoDB
- Big-data and Hadoop

#### **Soft Skills:**

- Time management
- Project management
- Attention to details
- Critical thinking
- Problem solving
- Organizational skills
- Interpersonal skill
- Written and verbal Communication skill
- Teamwork and collaboration